Guide to the United Workers Union-Independent Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- Press and Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Morales Grievance: Press, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Morales Grievance: Leaflets, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Correspondence (1 of 2), 1974-1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Correspondence (2 of 2), 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- United Workers Organizer, Volume II Number 2, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- United Workers Organizer, Volume II Number 3, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Coalition for Protective Legislation, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Third World Women's Coalition, 1971-1981 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Events, General Correspondence, Organizing Materials, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Final Argument for Rosa Morales, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Coalition for Protective Legislation, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Press Releases, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Strike, Recognition by Higher Education Personnel Board, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- United Workers Organizer, Volume II Number 1, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Photos and CDs, 1973-1981 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Buttons, 1973-1981 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee: Strike and Survival Handbook, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Morales Grievance: Press, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Fundraiser for Rosa Morales, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Publications and Press Releases: Staff Rights Organizing Committee and United Workers Union- Independent, 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Luislyn (Poo) Caires Grievance, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Anniversaries, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Agendas and Minutes, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Articles: State Workers, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Daily Articles, 1973-1976 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Bill of Rights Committee, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Goals, Strategy and Organization, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Speeches of Steering Committee, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Coors Beer Boycott, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Educationals, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Average Monthly Salary for all Classified Staff, circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Notes on Feminist Community, circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Financial Reports, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Clarence Grievance, circa 1973 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Correspondence to UWU- I, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Yolanda Alaniz Correspondence to Members, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Educational Opportunity Program Letter to Labor Organizations, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Report on Comparable Worth Study (Willis Study) by Lois Harris, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Brochures, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Statement on 1980 Affirmative Action Master Plan, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Anniversary Program and Financial Report, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Board of Regents Biennial Operating Budget, 1976-1979 (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Brochure Fonts, Designs, circa 1977 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee: Committees, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Faculty Senate Ad Hoc Committee, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Speeches: Monica Hill, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Research Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 1, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 2, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 3, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 4, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 5, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 6, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 7, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Organizer: Vol. 1, No. 8, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Pamphlet: U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare on Civil Rights, 1964-1970 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Harborview Medical Center Membership, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- House Bill No. 761, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Higher Education Personnel Board Meeting Agendas and Informational Bulletins, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Higher Education Personnel Board, 1973-1977 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Higher Education Personnel Board: Reclassification and Salary Adjustments, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Publication By University Hospital: Hospital Highlights, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Higher Education Personnel Board: Analysis of Distribution of Employees into Salary Ranges, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Speech: Monica Hill: International Women's Day, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Proposed Bylaw Changes, Union Officer Job Descriptions, Elections, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Job Descriptions, Benefits/Socials, Financial Reports, Elections, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Leaflet: 'Defend Free Speech' Rosa Morales Hearing, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Leaflet: 'Join the Friday Picket Against Racism and Sexism' Rosa Morales, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Press Release: End of Strike, Formation of a Union, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Leaflet: 'Public Meeting: Fight University Strike Reprisals', 1974 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Leaflet: 'United Workers are Sitting In', Office of Personnel Director Dave Williams, Strike Pay, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Leaflet: 'Public Meeting: Fight University Strike Reprisals' Edition II, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Leaflet: 'Reprisals Must be Reversed', Office of President Cartwright, Strike Pay Cont'd, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Poster: 'United Works Union- Independent is on the move', 1974 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Leaflet: 'UWU-I Stopped Management' John McDonald Grievance, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Leaflet: 'Starve or Freeze? Food Service Workers Should Not Have to Choose This Winter', 1974 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- Leaflet: 'A Victory for Food Service Workers, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 34)
- Leaflet: 'Sign the Petition for a $200 Raise', 1975 (Box 10, Folder 35)
- Leaflet: 'United Workers Supports State Employees Strike', 1975 (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Leaflet: '$200/mo. Raise- Before the Legislator; We Did It!', 1975 (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Poster: 'State Workers: Fight For a Living Wage!' Support for House Bill #761, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Protective Legislation, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 39)
- Organization Petitions, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 40)
- Instruction Notebook: Strike Headquarters: Central Control, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Forms: Arrest Calls, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 42)
- Instructions for Arrest Calls, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 43)
- Form: Letter to Boss, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 44)
- Form: Childcare, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 45)
- Things to Remember When Working with Small Children, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Information to Parents on Childcare, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 47)
- Information Sheet on Picketers, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 48)
- Strike Headquarters Rules and Regulations, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 49)
- United Workers Victory Bulletin, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Grievance Report Form, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 51)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Petition, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 52)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee State-Wide Conference Registration Form, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 53)
- Leaflet: 'Unfair Labor Practice? Are You Being Harrassed on the Job?', 1973 (Box 10, Folder 54)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Statements to Groups and Organizations, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 55)
- Legal Materials: Arrests, Laws, Collective, and Legal Action, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 56)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee: Organizing Materials, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 57)
- Letters From University of Washington Administration, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 58)
- Leaflet and Letter from Dissidents, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 59)
- Research Materials, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 60)
- Endorsements, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 61)
- Faculty Senate Report, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 62)
- National Organization for Women Statement on HEPB Reclassification System, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 63)
- Statewide Organizing, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 64)
- Correspondence, Criticism of Research, and Endorsements, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 65)
- Higher Education Personnel Board Meeting Minutes and Reclassification Plan Details, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 66)
- Higher Education Personnel Board Guidelines, circa 1973 (Box 10, Folder 67)
- Classified Staff Association, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 68)
- Washington Federation of State Employees Reports, Etc., 1973 (Box 10, Folder 69)
- Other Unions, 1972-1973 (Box 10, Folder 70)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Letter to Faculty: Invitation to Join/Support Strike, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 71)
- Statewide Organizing: Strategy and Goals, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 72)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Strike: Correspondence, Press Releases, Press Coverage, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 73)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee: Various Injunctions Against Higher Education Personnel Board, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 74)
- Elimination of Veteran Preference in Layoffs/Re-employment, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 75)
- Petition to the Legislature on State Employee Salaries, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 76)
- Analysis of Childcare: Yola Alaniz, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 77)
- Salary Recommendations for Classified Staff, 1976-1978 (Box 10, Folder 78)
- Leaflets, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 79)
- Press Coverage, Publications, and President Yolanda Alaniz' Correspondence, 1976-1980 (Box 10, Folder 80)
- Salary Proposal, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 81)
- United Workers Union- Independent: Statements, 1975-1980 (Box 10, Folder 82)
- AFSCME Statewide Strike: Preparation and Support, 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 83)
- Strike and Survival Handbook; 'Union Maid' Song, Circa 1975 (Box 10, Folder 84)
- Letterhead Ideas, Information Bulletin, Meeting Summary, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 85)
- Washington Federation of State Employees, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 86)
- Leaflet: Equal Pay for Equal Work in Dollars and Cents, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 87)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee: October Reclassifications, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Preamble and Anti-Layoff Literature, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Strike Handbooks and Information Sheets, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- January 1974 Press releases and Events (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Rape and Other Violent Crimes Against Women, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Letter to David Williams from Yvette Winters, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Newsletters: How to Write and Organize, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Fink Faction, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Cartwright Letter, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Cartwright Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Letters to All Staff, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Faculty Senate Ad Hoc Committee Report, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Rita Cooper Memo on Affirmative Action, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee: Research Committee, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Samples of Newsletter Rough Drafts: Historical, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Higher Education Personnel Board Letters, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Classified Staff Association and WFSE Local 1488 Leaflets, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee Minutes, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- The National Organization for Women Examines the HEPB Plan: Report 1, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Schedule and Duties Changes; Disciplinary Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Grievances, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Press Coordinator: Correspondence and Press Releases, 1974-1981 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- History: Staff Rights Organizing Committee Strike, 1973-1974 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- Leaflets, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Press Releases, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Staff Rights Organizing Committee: November, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Leaflet/Poster for Public Forum: Public Employees and the Right to Strike, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Education Opportunity Program, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Telephone Switchboard Raise, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Mary Reeves Suspension and Grievance, 1975-1980 (Box 11, Folder 32)
- Window Washer Layoffs, 1976-1979 (Box 11, Folder 33)
- The Daily on Union Issues, 1973-1977 (Box 11, Folder 34)
- Drafts: Grievance Procedure and Employee Rights, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 35)
- Daily: 'Resignation of HUB Manager not all voluntary', 1977 (Box 11, Folder 36)
- Responses to Employee Complaints: Switchboard and Dietary, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Window Washers Grievance: Layoffs, 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 38)
- David Harris: Discrimination Complaint Against Bellevue School District, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 39)
- Rosa Morales: Correspondence with James Vasquez, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 40)
- Childcare Coordinating Office, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 41)
- Rikansrud's Decision on Switchboard Grievance: May 27, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 42)
- Grievance Policy and Amended Bylaws, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 43)
- Minutes, Financial Statements, Membership Lists, Dues, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 44)
- Financial Statements, Minutes, Press Releases, 1974-1980 (Box 11, Folder 45)
- General Fund, 1974-1981 (Box 11, Folder 46)
- Rosa Morales Defense Fund, 1977-1980 (Box 11, Folder 47)
- Switchboard Grievance and Notes, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 48)
- Switchboard: Staff Employee Complaint; following Correspondence, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 49)
- Meeting Notices, Leaflets, Agendas, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 50)